# Curriculum Vitae

Name: James Ian Gibbs

Address: 8 West Close, Fernhurst, Haslemere, Surrey, GU273JR

Home Telephone: 01428 653434 Mobile: 07871 188025

E-mail: jamesigibbs180@gmail.com

Date of birth: 26 September 1998

#### **Personal Profile**

I am James Gibbs and I have strong communication and interpersonal skills, with an ability to build positive working relationships. I have a great passion for the outdoors, and I have experience working within the leisure industry and guest relations. I am positive and hardworking, and I always strive to achieve the highest standard possible, at any given task. I have the ability and experience to relate to a wide range of people. I enjoy learning new things and I am very enthusiastic and determined and would be a dedicated worker for any business.

## **Key Skills/Achievements**

- Communication I am an effective communicator. I am a good listener and have good interpersonal skills. I enjoy talking to people and learning from others.
- Team working I can work collaboratively with others from a wide range of backgrounds. I can use my initiative and work unsupervised, when required.
- In 2017 successful completion of Level 3 Extended Diploma in Outdoor Education and gained various outdoor qualifications (see below).
- In 2015, I competed at national level ski slalom racing (came 2<sup>nd</sup> at regional level)
- IT skills I am confident in MS Office, Excel, Outlook and PowerPoint

## **Employment and Work Experience**

- Apr 2016 to present. Marwell Activity Centre, Owslebury, Winchester. I am a seasonal instructor at Marwell Activity Centre, where I lead a large variety of land and water-based activities including climbing, kayaking, canoeing, raft building high ropes course and multiple team building and taster seasons. I work with all ages both children and adults including people with learning difficulties and people for disadvantaged backgrounds. I also help to train new staff members and I am responsible for ensuring the all-terrain quad bikes operate safely and train on the bikes' capabilities and responses, which often vary due to weather, terrain, load and speed. I also assist in the catering for up to 200 clients, serving and clearing food.
- Dec 2018 Mar 2019. White Lion Hotel Ambleside, Cumbria. Working under the general guidance of the Bar Manager, I assisted in the smooth running of the bar area to deliver a high standard of service and customer satisfaction. I operated the till and took cash, ensuring the float and till procedures were carried out in accordance with company policy. I was responsible for keeping the bar clean and tidy, collecting empty plates and glasses. I prepared the bar for service, restocking wines and spirits and delivered food and drinks to customers at tables. I dealt with guest complaints in a friendly and efficient manner and provided a professional, friendly and

courteous service to all customers.

2013 – 2016. Various work experiences. I assisted a local estate management business, coppicing
and preparing sustainable firewood. I also had experience working with a local business
specializing in the provision of inflatable and soft play products for parties, festivals, fetes etc. I
also enjoyed working with Grayswood Nursery and Forest School, where I contributed to a
program of activities for under-fives.

### **Education and Training**

- Sparsholt College (Sept 2016 to Jul 2017) Outdoor education level 3 (extended) diploma, passed with distinction.
  - → RYA Powerboat Level 1 (Jan 2017)
  - → QA Level 2 Award in Emergency First Aid at Work (Feb 2017)
  - → BMC Climbing Wall Award Training (Mar 2017)
  - → BCU Foundation Safety and Rescue Training (Mar 2017)
  - → BCU 2 Star Award in Kayaking and Canoeing (Mar 2017)
  - → UKCC Level 1 Certificate in Paddle sport coaching (Mar 2017)
  - → Sport Coach UK Safeguarding and Protecting Children (Jun 2014 and updated in Apr 2017)
  - → EASI Level 1 Quad Bike Supervisor (Apr 2017)
  - → EASI RIDER ATV safety training course
  - → Archery GB Instructor Award (Apr 2018)
- Sparsholt College (Sept 2015 to Jul 2016) Outdoor education level 3 diploma Distinction
- Midhurst Rother College (2010 2015) 7 GCSEs in Information Communication Technology (B), Additional Science (B), Product Design (C), Physical Education(C), English Language (C), Mathematics (C), Core Science (C)

#### **Other Interests**

• Whenever I have the opportunity, I am outdoors. I enjoy skiing and snow sports and competitive downhill mountain biking. I have developed a love of climbing both indoors and outdoors. I also participate in a variety of watersports including paddle sports and power boating.

#### References:

Available on request.

- Graham Marks, Activities Manager, Marwell Activity Centre
- Kathryn Hodson, Head of Investigations, The Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria

Motoring offence, February 2019, can be discussed at interview.